# ALIMUHAMMAD

SENIOR FULL STACK REACT DEVELOPER



ali@alimuhammad.ca



www.alimuhammad.ca



437-538-5855



Toronto, ON



## **SUMMARY**

I am a Senior Full Stack React Developer with well over 12 years of professional experience in developing web applications and beautiful websites from scratch. I have a Bachelor of Computer Science from the University of Toronto. My journey as a web developer has been impressive and I continue to grow and learn every day. I am a great fit for any startup or web agency, with my range of skills I have the ability to take on any size project or client and deliver a product or website that meets today's web standards and expectations.



### **EDUCATION**

# **University of Toronto**

BS in Computer Sciences Sep 2002 – April 2006



# **CERTIFICATION**

- Zend Certified PHP Engineer
- Microsoft Certified Specialist with HTML5,
   CSS3 and JavaScript
- Adobe Certified Expert

I'm seeking a full time, challenging and creative role as a Full Stack Web Developer at a company who can benefit from the 12 years of experience I gained at some well-known companies in the Toronto area. In my next role I would like to take on more responsibility and work towards being in a position where I might be able to manage a small team while continuing to learn and grow as a Full Stack Web Developer.

# **CORE COMPETENCIES**

Web Application Development • Software Engineering • Computer Information Systems

Beck-End & Front-End Development • Single-Webpage Application • Database Development

Advanced Coding • Troubleshooting & Debugging • Testing & Analysis • Solution Design

Leadership • Communication • Adaptability • Teamwork • Problem Solving • Goal-Oriented

# SKILLS

#### **PROGRAMMING**

- Knowledge of OOP / Design Patterns
- Expert in PHP, Proficient in MVC
- Web Services, API, WSDL, JSON, SOAP, XML

### DATABASES

- Relational Databases
   MySQL, SQL
- NoSQL Databases
   MongoDB, Reddis

#### **WEB RELATED**

- VueJs, React, jQuery, VanillaJs
- HTML5, CSS3, AJAX, Bootstrap
- AnimateJS, BounceJS, TweenMax,
- Lodash

# METHODOLOGIES:

UML, Agile, Scrum

#### **FRAMEWORKS**

- Laravel, Codelgniter, Yii, Zend, Symphony, AngularJs, ExpressJs
- CMS / ECommerce Systems (WordPress, OpenCart3, Joomla, Drupal, Concrete5)

#### LANGUAGES

• PHP, JavaScript, NodeJs

### SERVER SOFTWARE

- Linux (Debian, Ubuntu, CentOS)
- LAMP, XAMPP, Apache, Nginx,
- Amazon AWS (S3, EC2, RDB, Route53)
- SSH, cPanel, FTP

# SOFTWARES

- Git (Github, GitLab, BitBucket)
- PhpStorm, Visual Studio Code, Sublime
- Photoshop, XD, Illustrator, Sketch, InDesign

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### ROGERS COMMUNICATIONS

SENIOR FULL STACK REACT DEVELOPER

Store Management Application – Brampton, Ontario Sep 2015 to Present

**Overview:** With over 233 Canada wide Rogers Stores, Rogers required a robust Store Management Application to manage all the stores. Built on React, Node, integrated with multiple Rogers API's and sitting on AWS is an application that can fully manage all aspects of any Rogers Store, this includes store maintenance, audits and finding nearby contractors and much more.

**Environment:** React, Redux, Express, Node, Javascript, JSON, HTML5, CSS3, AWS, Rogers API's, Google Maps, Photoshop, Git, Agile, Webpack, RESTful API's, Jest/Enzyme.



#### **ROGERS COMMUNICATIONS**

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER

Customer Retention Tool – Brampton, Ontario Nov 2012 to Aug 2015

**Overview:** There are times when customers want to switch from Rogers to Bell or another service provider, this is where our Customer Retention Tool comes into play. Built on a custom PHP framework supported by JavaScript and very easy to use UI/UX interface, it's a tool Rogers Customer Service Reps rely on every day to keep customers using Rogers services.

**Environment:** PHP, Vanila JavaScript / JQuery, AJAX, MySQL, JSON, HTML, CSS, Rogers API's, Google Maps, Photoshop, Git, Agile.

# **CLIMAX MEDIA**

FULL STACK WEB / WORDPRESS DEVELOPER

HONDA, ACURA AND CANON - Toronto, ON May 2006 - Oct 2012

**Overview:** I started my career working at Climax Media because I wanted to learn from an agency who has a track record going above and beyond. I was given an opportunity to work on some amazing well-known brands such as Honda, Acura and Canon. As a developer at Climax, we create unique experiences based on customer data and analytics to deliver products that solve real world problems.

**Environment:** PHP, MySQL, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, JQuery, AJAX, WordPress, Joomla, Codeignitor, YIIFramework.

## **REFERENCE**

Available on Request